{
    "section": "Collision Avoidance",
    "section_number": "1",
    "questions": [
        {
            "index": "01",
            "question": "Which statement is true with regard to aircraft converging at approximately the same altitude?",
            "answers": {
                "1": "A jet airliner has the right of way over all other aircraft.",
                "2": "An aircraft towing objects has the right of way over all power-driven heavier-than-air aircraft.",
                "3": "An aeroplane has the right of way over all other aircraft which are converging from the left.",
                "4": "Aeroplanes towing gliders must give way to helicopters."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "2",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "02",
            "question": "When two aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude",
            "answers": {
                "1": "both aircraft shall alter heading to the left.",
                "2": "the aircraft on the right shall avoid the other by descending.",
                "3": "the aircraft that has the other on its right shall give way.",
                "4": "the aircraft that has the other on its left shall give way."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "3",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "03",
            "question": "When two aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude, which statement applies?",
            "answers": {
                "1": "Gliders shall give way to helicopters.",
                "2": "Aeroplanes shall give way to power-driven heavier-than-air aircraft.",
                "3": "Gliders shall give way to aeroplanes.",
                "4": "Power-driven heavier-than-air aircraft shall give way to gliders."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "04",
            "question": "When two aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude, which statement applies?",
            "answers": {
                "1": "Gliders shall give way to helicopters.",
                "2": "Aeroplanes shall give way to helicopters.",
                "3": "Helicopters shall give way to aeroplanes.",
                "4": "Helicopters shall give way to gliders."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "05",
            "question": "When two aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude, which statement applies?",
            "answers": {
                "1": "Gliders shall give way to helicopters.",
                "2": "Aeroplanes shall give way to helicopters.",
                "3": "Helicopters shall give way to aeroplanes.",
                "4": "Gliders shall give way to balloons."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "06",
            "question": "When converging at approximately the same altitude",
            "answers": {
                "1": "balloons shall give way to hang gliders.",
                "2": "aeroplanes towing gliders shall give way to balloons.",
                "3": "balloons shall give way to gliders.",
                "4": "balloons shall give way to airships."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "2",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "07",
            "question": "When two power-driven heavier-than-air aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude,",
            "answers": {
                "1": "the one on the left has the right of way.",
                "2": "both shall alter heading to the left.",
                "3": "the one on the right has the right of way.",
                "4": "the one on the right shall give way by descending."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "3",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "08",
            "question": "When two aircraft are approaching head-on or approximately so and there is danger of collision, each pilot shall",
            "answers": {
                "1": "decrease airspeed.",
                "2": "increase airspeed.",
                "3": "alter heading to the right.",
                "4": "alter heading to the left."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "3",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "09",
            "question": "When overtaking an aircraft at your 12 o'clock position, at your altitude, you should",
            "answers": {
                "1": "climb.",
                "2": "descend.",
                "3": "alter heading to the right.",
                "4": "alter heading to the left."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "3",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "10",
            "question": "Two aircraft are on approach to land, the aircraft at the higher altitude shall",
            "answers": {
                "1": "have the right of way.",
                "2": "overtake the lower aircraft on the left.",
                "3": "give way.",
                "4": "complete a 360Â° turn to the right."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "3",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        }
    ]
}